there's no evidence that Cavanaugh was
guilty apart from one woman's testimony
why would she put herself through that
she wasn't telling the truth the
Democrats turned the whole process into
a show trial Cavanaugh was far too
partisan and angry in front of the
committee you can't abandon the rule of
law and submit to a mob mentality on the
left David you all right so this is a
kind of slightly experimental podcast
based on how do you hold the possibility
that both of those narratives are true
at the same time because the reason
we're doing this is because both Jordan
Pederson and some of the other members
of the intellectual dark web have had a
lot of pushback for their comments on
Cavanaugh especially Jordan Peterson
which is the first time I think we've
seen him like really under attack from
his audience and he addressed it last
night in his live event and it sort of
feels it's an intro because this is what
we've been talking about a lot in our
podcast it's like how do you have a
conversation that is not immediately
reactive goes beyond polarization I
think this is a really interesting
cultural moment to do that yeah for me
that's the most interesting question
right now about how this is all played
out with Peterson the Weinsteins and the
reaction that they've had from within
I'm not sure what one would call them
they're fans or fans of the IDW in
general but for me the whole point of
the IDW is that you can have
conversations in public it's a new way
of having conversations and implicit in
that is that you can have a conversation
without it devolving into reactivity
that's the entire point and so I was
actually quite disappointed to see the
fervor and the kind of angst enos and
aggression that was coming from within
you know the the same groups of people
or the same people who've been
supporting there was a lot more of a
reactivity than I would have thought
especially considering the entire point
of this is to be able to think out loud
in public in good faith which has not
happened with this
yeah Brett's wife Heather hiring put out
a really interesting tweet which was you
haven't demonstrated support for free
speech until you defend speech that you
hate and you haven't demonstrated
support or an understanding of nuance
and
you defend it even when your side is
winning and this whole idea about nuance
I think is being able to hold
contradictory thoughts that as Brett
said in another tweet both of the
outcomes are unacceptable and we're
being presented by the system outcomes
that are equally unacceptable like the
Hillary Trump election I think was a
kind of good example of that for this
it's it's the idea that any allegation
can destroy a man's career and needs to
be believed absolutely and weaponization
of those allegations is quite
unacceptable and you can't run a society
on that on that basis but equally this
is and this is where I personally come
down I'm going to sort of weighing up
all the evidence the most why this is
such a difficult situation is because
the Supreme Court is supposed to be
above politics and cavanaugh in his
defense to the Senate explicitly made it
political and attacked I'll read from
her from his from his comment this whole
two-week effort has been a calculated
orchestrated political hit fueled with
pent up anger about president Trump in
the 2016 election fear that was at
billons fairly stoked about my judicial
record revenge on behalf of the Clintons
and millions of dollars in money from
outside left-wing opposition groups that
may well all be true but he has to he is
going to be on the Supreme Court which
is going to have to rule on some of the
most politically charged issues how can
the Supreme Court when it is dragged
into that debate be seen as any kind of
arbiter and how do you pull out of this
us and them mentality which is what I
think Peterson was was alluding to when
he said that he thought cabinet should
withdraw I just want to go back to that
point of nuance that Heather hiring had
in her tweet which I thought was very
good being able to just hold things
without needing to find the right answer
or the answer that confirms you know my
previously held beliefs so obviously not
always easy and I think with the the
kavanah thing it's so emotionally
charged that people lose their grounding
very easily on both sides but that's the
other point is that I think there's for
all the flack that
I'm guilty of this is Sahel okay all the
flak directed towards the social justice
warrior kind of attitude and you know
the regressive left I see just as much
reactivity from the right and that for
me it's it's two sides of the same coin
I think this has to be a resolution
beyond that where it's a new genuinely
what the IDW is is supposed to be about
again a new way of thinking and I think
part of that new way of thinking is also
around taking responsibility for our
emotions in the moment and probably not
doing it online but that's another
conversation to have yeah it's the other
point that comes up as well like
Peterson I think has been the main
target of this because he has been
identified as on one side of this
culture divide and I think a lot of the
people who are following him see him as
an ally on that side of a culture divide
like fighting back against identity
politics and so he I think has suffered
probably more than maybe Eric or Brett I
mean they've got a lower profile anyway
but they're not seen as figureheads for
for something and but what's interesting
is that I think when Peterson went on
the marsh show and said we'll hang on
how and you can't and they were there
were a lot of people there being quite
dismissive of Trump's of course and he
said hang on you can't you can't just
write off fifty percent of your people
the same thing goes the other way and
that's basically what is happening on
the other side now is you've got to he
was saying look you've got to build a
dialogue with these people you've got to
build a dialogue with Trump supporters
if you're on if you're more on the kind
of Hillary or the Democrat side
well you can't if you support him in
that message of yes well you've got to
have these conversations you can't then
turn around and say well actually no we
just need to defeat these other people
it's it's a contradiction otherwise you
have a divided country and there is no
way of pulling out of this tailspin of
polarization I've read a few things
actually suggesting that Eric and Brett
and possibly Peterson as well that there
was an intent I'm not sure it's true I
think the interesting idea that there's
kind of an intentional this was all
intentional in order to in a sense reach
out an olive branch and separate the
wheat from the chaff
of who
interested in this purely because it
happens to support their political
agenda or Hugh's interested but they
genuinely want another conversation I
don't know but I think it's an
interesting idea and what I think's
interesting about it is that it does
this process does in a way separate the
wheat from the chaff of who's who's
ready to leave ideology at the door to
it agree to a large enough dick we all
have an ideology or somewhere but to a
large enough degree where you can listen
to something that challenges you and go
hmm yeah not sure but let's keep
thinking and talking about it and that's
also for people watching this it's like
we're we're thinking aloud and it's an
ongoing conversation I don't expect that
what we're putting forward we're not
saying this is the truth but we think
it's a valuable addition we think this
is a valuable cultural moment to be able
to say how can we how can we see things
from multiple perspectives in a way
while holding on to truth while holding
on to what is what is actually going on
this other thing that that just I was
reminded of is what I got a sense of but
it was very interesting watching this be
kind of the one of the first times that
Peters Peterson gets a lot of flack from
people who don't like him really the
first time I can remember where he's
gotten a lot of flack from people who do
like him and it reminded me of well I -
words like projection and rejection so
as often in like couples therapies
there's there's a it's quite normal that
some in whatever kind of relationship
there's a kind of moment where you're
projecting all this stuff onto this
person so maybe like oh she's the best
woman in the world she's got all these
qualities that actually are things that
I'm painting onto her and then at some
point there's a realization of like oh
you're your own individual person and
you're not actually a container for all
my projections and you're not being the
way I want you to be so I'm going to
reject you and there's some element of
that happening I think in in this whole
conversation with the IDW in general
with Peterson as probably inevitably
what's going to happen at some point
well especially if Peterson is carrying
all of these kind of father projections
from so many people it's like well daddy
so something I don't agree with it's
like a very difficult dynamic to be
yeah to be exposed to so I think Brett
Weinstein had the most interesting
perspective of sort of meta perspective
which is that when the environment is
such that it selects for certain type of
behaviors the people who thrive in
environment other people that behave in
that are not the kind of people who put
national interest first for example
they're the people who know how to play
the polarization game like Kavanagh I
mean Cavanaugh there was a most
blatantly political speech by a kind of
aspiring Supreme Court justice that
anyone has ever heard so he played he
deliberately played the political game
looking to polarize knowing that the
Republicans had that none those numbers
and now he's a Supreme Court justice
what that does to America going forward
looks very dangerous from the outside if
the Supreme Court is called in to
adjudicate on an election for example
how can it and here's the despite
deciding vote
how can half the country have confidence
of that decision is being made for
anything other than political reasons it
just looks like it just looks like the
an accelerating process and that's the
concern that I think Brett probably has
has the most interesting take on of
where does this go going forward as this
continues to spiral
it really looks almost impossible for
for anyone to come up to or if there's
an interesting
he also frames it in what an opportunity
what an opportunity for someone to come
in and be a hero that could have been
Cavanaugh to say look I'm willing to
I've been vindicated I but I put the
national interest first
but as Brett says the kind of people put
the national interest first are not
selected for in this environment so it's
pretty scary